(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-10T09:25:03.780370",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリティでキュアキュア ふたりのプリッキュア〜！
Pretty with cure cure, the two of us are pretty cure ~!
一難去って、また一難 ぶっちゃけありえない！！
One danger coming after another is totally unbelievable!!
制服着ててもふたりは むちゃくちゃタフだしい
Even in our school uniforms, we're both amazingly tough,
お互いのピンチを乗り越えるたび 強く近くなるね☆
and when we overcome tough spots together, we grow closer!
your best ! my best !
Your best! My best!
生きているから失敗なんてメじゃない！
That's how we live, so failure's no big deal!
笑う門に福来るでしょっ！
It seems good luck comes to those who smile!
ネガティブだってブッ飛ぶぅ〜！
Send negative feelings flying ~!
生命の花咲かせて！ 思いっきり〜もっとバリバリ！！
Let the flower of life bloom! With everything we've got ~ work harder!!
プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリティでキュアキュア
Pretty with cure cure,
ふたりのプリッキュア〜！
the two of us are pretty cure ~!
やべぇ マイべぇ 生きてるんだから
Ya-bei! My-bei! Because we're alive,
失敗なんてないって めっちゃない！
failure's no big deal at all!
笑う門に福来たるでしょ ネガティブだって
Good luck comes to those who smile, so let's send
ブッ飛ぶ命の花咲かせて
negative thoughts flying and let life's flowers bloom!
思いっきりもっとバリバリ！
With everything we've got, work even harder!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリティでキュアキュア ふたりのプリキュア！
Pretty with cure cure, the two of us are pretty cure!
Hey everybody!
Yeah!
Are you ready?
Let's go!
Counteraction rising
Yeah we are ready for the punch line
There's no use with all your gimmicks
So check this out!
Login you damned ones crush the wont you compromise
The noise comes we are ready to bow
What about the antidote for the jammed and hypnotized
Rend the lie that covers who's the real sucker now
咲き乱れた花のように 鮮やかな痛み抱き
Embracing vivid pain like scattered blooming flowers,
佇む街を抜けて 迷いのセリフは捨てて
leaving the lingering town behind and tossing hesitation aside,
還らない声よ響け we say wow wow wow wow
let unreturning voices echo, we say wow wow wow wow
database database just living in the database wow wow
The wall of pure fiction's cracking in my head
And the addiction of my world still spreads
In the database database i'm struggling in the database wow wow
It doesn't even matter if there is no hope
As the madness of the system grows
database database just living in the database
Counteraction rising
Yeah we are ready for the punch line
There's no use with all your gimmicks
So check this out!
Login you damned one's
咲き乱れた花のように 鮮やかな痛み抱き
Embracing vivid pain like scattered flowers
佇む街を抜け 出逢いのセリフは捨て
Leaving the lingering town, throwing away hesitant lines
還らない声よ響け
Let the unreturning voice echo
We say wow wow wow wow
Database, database
Just living in the database wow wow
The wall of pure fiction's cracking in my head
And the addiction of my world still spreads
In the database, database
I'm struggling in the database wow wow
It doesn't even matter if there is no hope
As the madness of the system grows
Crack in the key for the real clue
Mass redemption reigning on
But we know we've been longing for this
Cut it out the plot that deceived you
Drop the rebel sound shut the system down
Reveal the never found now
引き裂かれたとしても 虚構とも現実とも
Even if torn apart, whether fiction or reality
見えるガレキの中で 戦い続ける だけ
Just keep fighting in the visible rubble
Get damn all from big airheads
Yeah you get damn all from big airheads
重なる 世界でたがえる 心に灯をともして
Lighting a fire in the surging heart across overlapping worlds
Database, database
Just living in the database wow wow
The wall of pure fiction's cracking in my head
And the addiction of my world still spreads
In the database, database
I'm struggling in the database wow wow
It doesn't even matter if there is no hope
Just say wow wow wow wow
時に計算高さは蛇足 da calculator
Sometimes being too calculated is unnecessary, da calculator
統計にゆさぶられたまま消えていった
Disappearing while shaken by statistics
そう なりたくないちゃ database
If you don't want to become like that, database
だけに頼らず磨き自分のペース
Don't just rely on it, polish your own pace
Get damn all from big airheads
Yeah you get damn all from big airheads
Please don't say "you are lazy"
だって 本当は crazy
Because actually we are crazy
白鳥たちは そう 見えないところで バタ足するんです
Swans paddle frantically where nobody can see
本能に順応 忠実 翻弄も重々承知
Obedient to instinct, fully aware of being toyed with
前途洋々だし… だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
Our future is bright... so we take breaks sometimes
この目でしっかと見定め得 行き先 地図上マークして
Seeing clearly with our own eyes, marking the map
近道あればそれが王道 はしゃる翼があれば上等
Shortcuts are best, and wings to fly are even better
ヤバ爪割れた グループで補修した それだけでなんか達成感
Nail broke, fixed it with glue, a sense of achievement
大事なのは自分可愛がること 自分愛さないと他人も愛せない
Loving yourself is key; love yourself to love others
Please don't say "you are lazy"
だって 本当は crazy
Because actually we are crazy
能ある鷹は そう 見えないところにピック隠すんです
A talented hawk hides its talons out of sight
想像に一生懸命 現実人は絶体絶命
Trying hard in imagination, reality is desperate
発展途中だし… だから不意にピッチ外れるんです
Still developing... so we sometimes go out of tune
その目に映らないだけで やる気はメーター振り切って
Even if it doesn't show, our motivation is maxed out
いつでも全力で夢見て その分全力で眠って
Always dreaming with all our might, sleeping just as hard
やりちょい痩せた 調子づいて喰った それだけでなんで？敗北感
Lost weight, got cocky and ate—why feel defeated?
すかさず目標下方修正して 柔軟に臨機応変 七変化が勝ち
Quickly revising goals downward, flexibility brings victory
Please don't say "you are lazy"
だって 本当は crazy
Because actually we are crazy
孔雀たちは そう ここというとき 美を魅せるんです
Peacocks show their beauty when it counts
五臓六腑 満身邁進 願望は痩身美人
Body and soul moving forward, desiring beauty
誘惑多発だし… だからやけに意志砕けちゃうんです
Temptations everywhere... so willpower easily breaks
ヤバまさか赤点？！ いやギリセーフ！ それだけでなんと全能感
Uh oh, failing grade?! Barely passed! Such omnipotence
大事なのは自分認めてくこと 自分許さないと他人手許せない
Acknowledge yourself; forgive yourself to forgive others
Please don't say "you are lazy"
だって 本当は crazy
Because actually we are crazy
白鳥たちは そう 見えないところで バタ足するんです
Swans paddle frantically where nobody can see
本能に順応 忠実 翻弄も重々承知
Obedient to instinct, fully aware of being toyed with
前途洋々だし… だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
Our future is bright... so we take breaks sometimes
ふー
*sighs*
ライブの時間か…
Time for the live...
あれ？ あれ？
Huh? Huh?
え、きのこ生えてる！ 頭から！
Eh? There's a mushroom! On my head!
え… こわ…
E... scary...
なにこれ？
What is this?
つんつん… なにこれ…
Poke poke... what is this...
まいっか
Oh well.
うん
Yeah.
いただきます
Let's eat.
1(ワン)、2(ツー)、準備 おっけー?
1, 2, preparation, ready?
3(スリー)、4(フォース)で跳び飛ばして
3, 4, let's jump right in!
全部さ フイにしちゃったっていいじゃん?
Isn't it fine to just take it all in?
どうせ何が変わるわけじゃないし
After all, nothing's really going to change anyway.
邁進! 発射オーライ、未来!
Full speed ahead! Launching on all-clear, future!
Yeah!
ステップあやふや どうして?ルルリララ
Stepping unsteadily, why? Rurirurara...
迷っていたってさ、しょーがないじゃん?
Getting lost isn't an option, is it?
やめて あえて 攻めて 確かめて
Stop, face it, attack, make sure,
酔狂まるで足りないや
Drunk on it, as if it's not enough.
弾き出すフレーズ解き放って
Bursting out, unleashing the phrase,
ほらほら楽しいことしたもん勝ち!
Hey, whoever has the most fun wins!
探しに行くんだ セツナトリップ
Let's go find it, Setsuna Trip!
飛べない わけじゃない まだ内緒のハートに Dive!
It's not that I can't fly, I'm just diving into my inner heart!
脇目も振らず 出たとこ勝負!
Ignoring the onlookers, it's a winner-take-all!
手痛い 停滞 撤退はしない
No aching, lingering, or backing down.
生き急げ 全開少女
Live fast, go all out, maiden!
寝ても 覚めても その刹那 飼い馴らして
Sleeping or waking, in that instant, I'm getting used to it.
そろそろどうも 限界症状
Before long, it's a limit-break syndrome,
即効性の Trip に夢中
Hooked on this instant trip!
フワフワリ もうちょっと
Fluffy, just a little more,
フラフラリ もうちょっと 甘えて
Faltering, just a little more, wrapping it up.
あらあらやっちまったベイベー
Oops, what a blunder, baby!
きって発展性も何もあるまいに
There's got to be some potential too,
毎日!懲りないなあ……
Every single day! I never learn...
早送りのように過ぎゆく日々も
Days passing by like fast-forward,
まだまだあーやってこーやって溺れたいんだ
Still, I want to keep on running and losing myself in it.
如何せん 不完全 トリップガール
How about that, an imperfect trip girl?
代わる代わる がな立てる現実(Real)を BANG!
Replacing reality over and over with a BANG!
抗え きっと トリックがある
Resist, there's bound to be a trick to it.
迷路 音色 夜色に紛れて
Lost, tone, blending into the night color.
うら若き 明日ある少女
Immature, a girl with a tomorrow,
寝たふり Free 耳を塞ぐ
Pretending to sleep, free, covering my ears.
「あー、聴こえんなぁい!」
"Hey, I can't hear you!"
甘美なバンビナ 夢見る少女
Sweet bunting, a dreaming girl,
そこに永遠があると信じて
Believing that eternity is right there,
頑張るだけ損じょうん
Trying hard just wastes it all,
なんとなし察しちゃうじょうん
You somehow end up realizing it anyway.
生まれた時にさ、配られていた手札が
The hand we were dealt when we were born—
「弱かったら終わりだって」
"If you're weak, it's over,"
先なんて知れてるって
As if I knew that from the start!
覆せやしないって!
Don't patch it up!
「あ ﾞー!もーっ!ギターッ!!」
"Ah, geez! Come on! Guitar!!"
わかっているんだ言い訳だって
I know it, that's just an excuse,
手札なんて自分次第なんだって
The cards you're dealt are up to you,
いつまでユメに逃げできてるんでしょ?
How long are you going to keep running away into dreams?
そろそろおはような時間だろう?
Isn't it about time to wake up?
目を覚ませ セツナトリップ
Open your eyes, Setsuna Trip!
飛べない わけじゃない 今眩しい 現実(Real)に Dive!
It's not that I can't fly, dive into the dazzling reality!
脇目も振らず 逃げずに勝負!
Ignoring the onlookers, facing it without running away!
絶対免れない 痛い よし ない
There's no escaping this pain, alright,
覚悟を決めて 負けずに生きるから!
Make up your mind and live on without losing!
甘美なバンビナ 夢見る少女
Sweet bunting, a dreaming girl,
そこに永遠があると信じて
Believing that eternity is right there,
頑張るだけ損じょうん
Trying hard just wastes it all,
なんとなし察しちゃうじょうん
You somehow end up realizing it anyway.
生まれた時にさ、配られていた手札が
The hand we were dealt when we were born—
「弱かったら終わりだって」
"If you're weak, it's over,"
先なんて知れてるって
As if I knew that from the start!
覆せやしないって!
Don't patch it up!
「あ ﾞー!もーっ!ギターッ!!」
"Ah, geez! Come on! Guitar!!"
わかっているんだ言い訳だって
I know it, that's just an excuse,
手札なんて自分次第なんだって
As if I'd know what cards I hold!
いつまでユメに逃げてるんでしょ?
How long am I going to keep escaping into dreams?
そろそろおやつの時間だろう?
It's about time I woke up.
目を覚ませ セツナトリップ
Open your eyes, Setsuna Trip!
飛べない わけじゃない 眩しい 現実(Real)に Dive!
It's not that I can't fly, dive into the dazzling reality!
脇目も振らず 月夜に勝負!
Ignoring the onlookers, it's a winner-take-all with the moon!
絶対負けない 期待はしない
I definitely won't let it end, I won't give up!
覚悟を決めて 負けずに生きるから!
I'll make up my mind and live on through it!
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
Shine bright!
呼び合う声を 合図に
With our calling voices as a signal,
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探しにいく スタートは何回だって
Going to search, no matter how many times we start over
ただ 独り言を綴ったんだって
I just strung together monologues...
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
Shine bright!
まだ頼りない予感を 歌おう
Let's sing of this still-unreliable premonition,
恥ずかしそうになんてないよ
there's nothing to be embarrassed about!
誰も解けないイマジネーション いつかまた逢えるおまじない
An imagination nobody can solve, a magic spell to meet again someday
あの日ゼロに始まったストーリー 数え切れない言の葉
The story that began at zero on that day, countless words
数えるような想いじゃないさ ほら今 “僕等” を一つと呼ぼう
It's not feelings you can just count—look, now let's call 'us' one!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! Shine bright!
悔しさも愛しさも 連れておいで 風 夢 羽
Bring along your frustrations and affection too—wind, dreams, feathers
飛び立てばさ ささやかな祈りは 光
if we take flight, our modest prayers will become light,
終わりなき兆し 君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
an endless sign. I can hold my head high knowing I found you.
ここから これから Our bright parade, parade!
From here, from now on—our bright parade, parade!
まだ頼りない予感を 歌おう 恥ずかしそうになんてないよ
Let's sing of this still-unreliable premonition, there's nothing to be embarrassed about!
誰も解けないイマジネーション いつかまた逢えるおまじない
An imagination nobody can solve, a magic spell to meet again someday
あの日ゼロに始まったストーリー 数え切れない言の葉
The story that began at zero on that day, countless words
数えるような思い出じゃないさ ほら今 僕らを一つと呼ぼう
It's not memories you can just count—look, now let's call 'us' one!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 美しいんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's so beautiful!
許し合える刹那 夜はきらめく
In the fleeting moment of mutual forgiveness, the night sparkles.
雨、晴れ、カレイド またとない空
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope—a sky like no other.
相応しい旅路とは 君に在ることさ
A fitting journey is simply being with you.
君に在ることなんだ
Yes, simply being with you.
“ただいま” を聞けば “おかえり” って叫ぶよ
When I hear 'I'm home,' I'll shout 'Welcome back!'
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that only natural?
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! Shine bright!
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ！
What fills the darkness is you, it's me!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! Shine bright!
悔しさも愛しさも 連れておいで 風 夢 羽
Bring along your frustrations and affection too—wind, dreams, feathers
飛び立てばさ ささやかな祈りは 光
if we take flight, our modest prayers will become light,
終わりなき兆し 君と飛び込んでいく
an endless sign. I'm diving in together with you,
素敵なスタートさ ここから これから
what a wonderful start—from here, from now on!
Our bright parade, parade!
まぶしい太陽を見上げた時 君に会いたくなったんだ
When I looked up at the dazzling sun, I found myself wanting to see you.
行くの？行かないの？
Are you going? Are you not going?
行っちまえばいいーじゃん
Just go already!
言えよ言いたいよ vs 言えない
Say it, I want to say it, versus I can't
裏か表か 底無しのクエストン
Front or back, a bottomless question
だけどどうしてどうにもこうにもこうにもどうしたい
But why can't I do anything about it, how do I want it?
ah-ha dig it, dig it
ah-ha dig it up
見ざる 言わざる 聞ざるでござる
See no evil, say no evil, hear no evil
君子、危うきに近寄らずデス
A gentleman stays away from danger, desu!
お願いされたら、やめたくなります
When asked, I suddenly want to quit
だったら、許す だったら、笑え
If so, I forgive. If so, smile.
こころの音が木霊する
The sound of the heart echoes
涙と希望のカーニバル
A carnival of tears and hope
生意気くらいの夜明けに
In a somewhat cheeky dawn
行かないで…行かないで…
Don't go... don't go...
泣かないで…泣かないで…
Don't cry... don't cry...
サラバ、昨日をぬぎすてて
Farewell, casting off yesterday,
勇気の声をふりしぼれ
Muster your courageous voice
「じぶん」という名の愛を知るために
To know the love named "yourself"
眠れない羊の群れよ
O flock of sleepless sheep,
迷えるこころの叫びを
The cry of a wandering heart,
振り返るな我らの世界はまだ始まったばかりだ
Look not back, our world has only just begun.
さびしい思いさせんじゃないぞ
Don't make me feel lonely!
やるの？ サボんの？ サボればいーじゃん！
Doing it? Skipping? Skipping is fine!
遭難しそうでまさかの号泣
Heading for shipwreck, weeping in surprise
ホメてますから、全力で。
I'm praising you, with all my might.
そしてどこまでもつづく夢をみた
And I dreamed a dream that goes on forever,
天使が舞い降りてきた
An angel came dancing down.
そしてどこまでもつづく空のもとで
And beneath a sky that goes on forever,
自由になりたい
I want to be free.
1, 2 and 3, 4, 5
get up, stand up free your soul
stand up and make some noise！
stand up and make some noise!
こころの音が木霊する
The sound of the heart echoes
涙と希望のカーニバル
A carnival of tears and hope
生意気くらいの夜明けに
In a somewhat cheeky dawn
揺らすんだ…揺らすんダ…
Shake it... shake it...
進むんだ…進むんだ…
Move forward... move forward...
サラバ、昨日をぬぎすてて
Farewell, casting off yesterday,
勇気の声をふりしぼれ
Muster your courageous voice
「じぶん」という名の愛を知るために
To know the love named "yourself"
眠れない羊の群れよ
O flock of sleepless sheep,
迷えるこころの叫びを
The cry of a wandering heart,
振り返るな我らの世界はまだ始まったばかりだ
Look not back, our world has only just begun.
ah-ha dig it, dig it
ah-ha dig it up
oh-ho do it, do it
oh-ho do it now, do it now, do it now
行くの？ 行かないの？
Are you going? Are you not going?
行っちまえばいいーじゃん
Just go already!
言えよ 言いたいよ vs 言えない
Say it, I want to say it, versus I can't
裏か 表か 底無しのクエストン
Front or back, a bottomless question
だけどどうしてどうにもこうにもこうにもどうしたい
But why can't I do anything about it, how do I want it?
ah-ha dig it, dig it
ah-ha dig it up
見ざる 言わざる 聞ざるでござる
See no evil, say no evil, hear no evil
君子、危うきに近寄らずデス
A gentleman stays away from danger, desu!
お願いされたら、やめたくなります
When asked, I suddenly want to quit
だったら、許す だったら、笑え
If so, I forgive. If so, smile.
こころの音が木霊する
The sound of the heart echoes
涙と希望のカーニバル
A carnival of tears and hope
生意気くらいの夜明けに
In a somewhat cheeky dawn
行かないで…行かないで…
Don't go... don't go...
泣かないで…泣かないで…
Don't cry... don't cry...
サラバ、昨日をぬぎすてて
Farewell, casting off yesterday,
勇気の声をふりしぼれ
Muster your courageous voice
「じぶん」という名の愛を知るために
To know the love named "yourself"
眠れない羊の群れよ
O flock of sleepless sheep,
迷えるこころの叫びを
The cry of a wandering heart,
振り返るな我らの世界はまだ始まったばかりだ
Look not back, our world has only just begun.
さびしい思いさせんじゃないぞ
Don't make me feel lonely!
やるの？ サボんの？ サボればいーじゃん！
Doing it? Skipping? Skipping is fine!
遭難しそうでまさかの号泣
Heading for shipwreck, weeping in surprise
ホメてますから、全力で。
I'm praising you, with all my might.
そしてどこまでもつづく夢をみた
And I dreamed a dream that goes on forever,
天使が舞い降りてきた
An angel came dancing down.
そしてどこまでもつづく空のもとで
And beneath a sky that goes on forever,
自由になりたい
I want to be free.
1, 2 and 3, 4, 5
get up, stand up free your soul
サラバ、愛しき悲しみたちよ
Farewell, my beloved sorrows,
行くのか？ 行かないのか？ 行っちゃえばいーじゃん
Go or not? Just go for it, right?
言えよ 言いたいよ vs 言えない
Say it, I want to vs I can't say it
裏か表か底無しのクエストーション
Heads or tails, a bottomless quest-ion
だけどどうしてどうもこうもこうも抱いちゃいたい
Even so, why do I want to hold you so badly?
ah-ha dig it, dig it
ah-ha dig it up
見ざる 言わざる 聞ざる でござる
See no, speak no, hear no evil
君子、危うきに近寄らずデス
A wise person stays away from danger
お願いされたら、やめたくなります
If you ask me to, I'll want to stop
だったら、許す、だったら、笑え
If so, forgive me, if so, smile
こころの声が木霊する
The voice of the heart echoes
涙と希望のカーニバル
A carnival of tears and hope
生意気くらいの夜明けに
In a brazen, youthful dawn
行かないで…
Don't go...
泣かないで…
Don't cry...
サラバ、昨日をぬぎすてて
Farewell, shedding yesterday,
勇気の声をふりしぼれ
Cry out with a voice of courage
「じぶん」という名の愛を知るために
To know love by the name of "myself"
眠れない羊の群れよ
Flock of sleepless sheep,
迷えるこころの叫びを
The cry of a straying heart
振り返るな我らの世界はまだ始まったばかりだ
Don't look back, our world has only just begun
さびしい想いさせってんじゃねえよ
Don't make me feel lonely!
やるのか？ サボるのか？ サボればいーじゃん！
Doing it? Skipping? Skipping's fine!
寂しい思いさせってんじゃねえよ
Don't make me feel lonely!
やるの？ サボるの？ サボればいーじゃん
Doing it? Skipping? Skipping's fine!
遭難そうでまごだぎの号泣
A shipwrecked, wailing distress call
ほめてますから全力で
Praising you with all my might
そしてどこまでもつづく夢を見た
And I saw a dream that goes on forever
天使が舞い降りてきた
An angel came fluttering down
そしてどこまでもつづく空のもとで
Under a sky that stretches on forever,
自由に生きたい
I want to live freely
1, 2 and 3, 4, 5 get up, stand up free your soul
1, 2 and 3, 4, 5 stand up and make some noise !
1, 2 and 3, 4, 5 stand up and make some noise!
oh-ho do it, do it
oh-ho do it now
こころの声が木霊する
The voice of the heart echoes
涙と希望のカーニバル
A carnival of tears and hope
生意気くらいの夜明けに
In a brazen, youthful dawn
揺らすんだ…
Shake it up...
進むんだ…
Move forward...
サラバ、昨日をぬぎすてて
Farewell, shedding yesterday,
勇気の声をふりしぼれ
Cry out with a voice of courage
「じぶん」という名の愛を知るために
To know love by the name of "myself"
眠れない羊の群れよ
Flock of sleepless sheep,
迷えるこころの叫びを
The cry of a straying heart
振り返るな我らの世界はまだ始まったばかりだ
Don't look back, our world has only just begun
ah-ha dig it, dig it
ah-ha dig it up
oh-ho do it, do it
oh-ho do it now,
do it now,
do it now
愛しき悲しみたちよでしたー！
That was "Aishiki Kanashimitachi yo"!
どうだったみんな？
How was it, everyone?
どうでした？どうでした？
How was it? How was it?
ちょっと、アバブライトパレードはですね、沙花叉が初めてジャケットに参加した全体曲ということで、
You know, for "Above Light Parade," since it was the first group song I participated in for my jacket,
結構思い出がありまして、ちょっと一人で歌うっていうのでもちょっと緊張したし、声震えてましたね。
I have a lot of fond memories. Singing it all by myself made me a bit nervous, and my voice was shaking.
大丈夫、大丈夫だったかな？
Is it okay? Was it alright?
そして、この次がトリガーはイコラブさんの曲で、王道アイドルって感じの曲なんですが、
And then, the next one, "Trigger," is an =LOVE song, sort of a royal idol-like song,
似合っててたかな？似合っててた？
did it suit me? Did it suit me?
どうだった？どうだった？どうだった？
How was it? How was it? How was it?
そして、沙花叉愛しき悲しみたちよを、ちょっとホロックスでね、
And then, for "Aishiki Kanashimitachi yo," with Holox, you know,
なんか、先輩モノってありません？ホロックスって。
aren't there senior-like things? Holox has that.
わかんない、あの、ヘルメットのせいかもしれない、わかんないんですけど、
I don't know, maybe because of the helmet, I don't know, but
なんかそんな感じがするから、ちょっと先輩物っぽい曲調を、なんか歌って踊りたいなと思ってて、
since it gives that kind of vibe, I wanted to sing and dance to a senior-ish song-style, so
どうだったか？似合ってた？あ、それ食らった？ありがとう！
How was it? Did it suit me? Ah, you liked it? Thank you!
ね、わかるよね？わかるよね？同じ？わかるよね？やっぱそうだと思ったんですよね。
Right, you get it, right? You get it, right? Same? You get it, right? I figured that's how it is.
なので、まあ自分的にはすごく似合ってて、みんな良い感じに歌って踊ってくれたんじゃないかなと思います。
So, personally I think it really suited me, and everyone sang and danced in a really good way.
ではですね、そう、あのヘルメットね。ではですね、ちょっとなんか変なぽいぽい感っていうか、
Now then, yes, about that helmet. Well then, I feel like things have settled down a bit with that strange carefree vibe,
余裕も落ち着いてきたような感じがしますし、この後も引き続きゲストパート行きたいと思いますので、
and since we're going to continue with the guest part after this,
応援よろしくお願いします！
please keep supporting us!
みんなよろっちゃんだよー！
Everyone, best regards!
信号は青なのだろうか
Is the traffic light blue,
それとも緑なのだろうか どっちなんだ？
or is it green? Which one is it?
曖昧なものははっきりさせたい
I want to make ambiguous things clear.
夕暮れ時の商店街の雑踏を通り抜けるのが面倒で
It's a hassle to walk through the crowded shopping district at dusk,
踏切を渡って遠回りして帰る
so I cross the railroad crossing and take a detour home.
放課後の教室は苦手だ その場にいるだけで分かり合えているようで
I'm not good at after-school classrooms, where just being there makes it seem like we understand each other,
話し合いにならないし白けてしまった僕は無口になる
but we can't really talk, and having lost interest, I fall silent.
言いたいこと言い合って解決しようなんて楽っていすぎるよ
Saying we should talk it out and resolve things is way too optimistic.
誰かが溜息をついた
Someone sighed.
そうそれが本当のの声だろう黒い羊そうだな僕がいなくなればいいんだ
Yes, that must be the true voice. A black sheep, right. It would be fine if only I were gone.
そうすれば止まってた針はまた動き出すんだろ？
If I do that, the stopped hands of the clock will start moving again, right?
全員が納得するそんな答えなんてあるものか！
Is there really an answer that everyone can agree on?!
反対が僕だけならいっそ無視すればいいんだ
If I'm the only one opposed, I might as well just be ignored.
みんなから説得されるほうが居心地悪くなる
Being persuaded by everyone makes it even more uncomfortable.
目配せしている仲間には僕は厄介者でしかない
To the companions exchanging glances, I'm nothing but a nuisance.
真っ白い群れに悪目立ちしている 自分だけが真っ黒な羊
Standing out in a pure white flock, I'm the only pitch-black sheep.
と言ったって同じ色に染まりたくないんだ
Even so, I don't want to be dyed the same color.
薄暗い部屋の明かりをつけるタイミングっていったいいつなんだろう？
When is the right time to turn on the light in a dim room?
スマホには愛のない過去だけが残っている
Only a loveless past remains on my smartphone.
人間関係の答え合わせなんか私にはできないし
I can't figure out the answer key to human relationships,
そこにいなければよかったと後悔する 人生の大部分は思うようにはいかない
and I regret not being there. Most of life doesn't go the way you want it to.
納得できないことばかりだし諦めろと諭されてたけど
I was told to give up since there are so many things I can't accept,
それならやっぱ納得なんかないままその度に何度も唾を吐いて
but if so, spitting out saliva every single time without ever accepting it—
噛みついていけませんか？
can't I keep biting back?
No no no no 全部僕のせいだ
No no no no, it's all my fault.
黒い羊そうだな 僕がいなくなればいいんだ
A black sheep, right. It would be fine if only I were gone.
そうすれば止まってた針はまた動き出すんだろ？
If I do that, the stopped hands of the clock will start moving again, right?
全員が納得するそんな答えなんてあるものか！
Is there really an answer that everyone can agree on?!
反対が僕だけならいっそ無視すればいいんだ
If I'm the only one opposed, I might as well just be ignored.
みんなから説得されるほうが居心地悪くなる
Being persuaded by everyone makes it even more uncomfortable.
目配せしている仲間には僕は厄介者でしかない わかっているよ
To the companions exchanging glances, I'm nothing but a nuisance. I know that.
白い羊なんて僕は絶対になりたくないんだ
I absolutely refuse to become a white sheep.
そうなった瞬間に僕は僕じゃなくなってしまうよ
The moment I do that, I'll stop being myself.
まわりと違うそのことで誰かに迷惑かけたか？
Did I cause trouble for anyone just by being different from the rest?
髪の毛を染めろと言うおとなは何が気にいらない？
What is it that adults who tell me to dye my hair dislike?
逆の象徴になるとでも思っているのか？
Do they think I'm becoming a symbol of rebellion?
自分の色とは違うそれだけで厄介者か？
Am I a nuisance just because my color is different from their own?
自らの真実を捨て白い羊のふりをする者よ
Those who throw away their own truth and pretend to be white sheep,
黒い羊を見つけ指を差して笑うのか？
will you find a black sheep, point fingers, and laugh?
それなら僕はいつでも そこで悪目立ちしてよう
Then I'll always stand out right here.
期待の裏には 予想通りの虚しさ
Expectations hide the emptiness of reality as expected.
あまりにも 強すぎて 受け入れ作業に時間をくって
It's all too much, and it takes time to process.
不都合でひどい頭痛 空回りの日々
A bad headache, days going in circles,
一つも灰なんて 残しちゃいけない...
I can't leave even a single trace of gray...
目眩がする程、眩しいあの世界
That dazzling, blinding world
鋭く胸に 突き刺さるよ
pierces sharply into my heart.
取り乱して 今夜眠れない
I'm so unsettled, I can't sleep tonight.
胸がざわついて半信半疑
My heart is racing, half in doubt.
泳いでみるのも、悪くないよ
Trying to swim along isn't bad either.
嘘ばかりの中どんな場所でも
No matter how much of a lie every place is,
自分は変わりゃしないのに
I won't change who I am.
普通の幸せ、普通の暮らし、普通って何?
Ordinary happiness, ordinary life, what is "ordinary"?
まばたきの隙間 こぼれてく dream in'
Spilling out between the blinking, dream in'
一粒残さず あつめて galaxy
Gather up every last bit into the galaxy
(flash flash) シトロン
(Flash, flash) Citron
(flash flash) 浮かべて
(Flash, flash) Floating
ムーンライトを 夢に見た ロマンチカ
Moonlight seen in a dream, a romance
(shake shake) かきまぜ
(Shake, shake) Stir it up
(shake shake) 溶かすんだ
(Shake, shake) Melt it down
ファンタジック ≒ リアル まわる マーブル
Fantasy vs. reality, a swirling marble
うららかに 光る 音色が おいで 誘い出すよ
Softly glowing melodies come and invite us out
うたかたに 消えないで シンフォニー
Don't let it fade away in a song, a symphony
つかまえたい planet lover
I want to catch it, planet lover
swing ! swing ! swing ! yey
Swing! Swing! Swing! Yeah!
あ 君と コズミック・フローティング
Ah, floating cosmically with you
曖昧に 揺れたい フィーリング
An ambiguous, swaying feeling
ミントグリーン の 風 と サイダーブルー の 地球(ほし) で
On the mint-green wind and cider-blue Earth
生まれた 恋 内緒 で 今夜 持ち出そう か
Shall we bring out this newborn love tonight?
(flash flash) つなげた
(Flash, flash) Connected
(flash flash) フィルム を
(Flash, flash) Film
水彩 の 空 に 透かして みたら
Looking through it against the watercolor sky
(shake shake) ネガイ と セカイ が
(Shake, shake) Negai and Sekai
手を 取って 踊りだしょ トワイライト
Hold hands and start dancing, twilight
つまみ に 誰か が 込めた
A melody someone poured into a pinch
愛 に 触れる メロディ
Touching love
またたきに 咲かせた イメージ で
An image that instantly bloomed
口ずさむ フレーズ
Phrares murmuring aloud
planet lover
swing ! swing ! swing ! yey
Swing! Swing! Swing! Yeah!
あ 君と コズミック・フローティング
Ah, floating cosmically with you
めくるめく 旋律 は 今 シグナル
The spinning melody is now a signal
星屑 が ちりばめて く きらめき と 遊ぶ の
Shooting stars scatter, playing with the sparkle
planet lover
swing ! swing ! swing ! yey
Swing! Swing! Swing! Yeah!
あ 君と コズミック・フローティング
Ah, floating cosmically with you
しゃしゃななななな なななななーなー
Shashananana...
Swing! Swing! Swing! Yeah!
しゃしゃななななな なななななーなー
Shashananana...
曖昧に揺れた日々
Days swaying ambiguously
コンビニエンスストアで 350mlの缶ビール買って
At the convenience store, bought a 350ml can of beer,
きみと夜の散歩 時計の針は0時を指してる
Taking a night walk with you, the clock hands point to midnight.
“クロノスタシス”って知ってる？
Do you know about "chronostasis"?
知らないときみが言う
You say you don't know.
時計の針が止まって見える現象のことだよ
It's when the clock hands appear to stop.
ラララハハオ〜
Lalalahaha...
holiday's midnight 少し汗ばんだ手のひら
holiday's midnight, slightly sweaty palms,
子供みたいな体温 誰もしらない場所に行きたい
childlike body temperature, I want to go somewhere nobody knows,
誰もしらない秘密を知りたい
I want to know a secret nobody knows.
街灯の下で きみの髪が ゆらゆら揺れて夢のようで
Under the street lights, your hair swings gently like a dream,
ゆらゆら揺れてどうかし てる
swings gently like something's off.
ラララハハオ〜
Lalalahaha...
holiday's midnight
今夜だけ忘れてよ 家まで帰る道 なんかさちょっとさ いい感じ
just forget for tonight, the way back home, it feels kinda nice.
街灯の下で きみの影が
Under the street lights, your shadow
ゆらゆら揺れて 夢のようで
swings gently like a dream,
ゆらゆら揺れて どうかしてる
swings gently like something's off.
ラララハハオ〜
Lalalahaha...
歩く速度が違うから bpm 83 に合わせて
Our walking pace is different, matching the bpm 83,
きみと夜の散歩 それ以上もう何も言わないで
taking a night walk with you, let's not say anything more.
“クロノスタシス”って知ってる？
Do you know about "chronostasis"?
知らないときみが言う
You say you don't know.
時計の針が止まって見える現象のことだよ
It's when the clock hands appear to stop.
ラララハハオ〜
Lalalahaha...
ゆらゆら揺れて 夢のようで
Swings gently like a dream,
ゆらゆら揺れて どうかしてる
swings gently like something's off.
コンビニエンスストアで 350mlの缶ビール買って
At the convenience store, bought a 350ml can of beer,
きみと夜の散歩 時計の針は0時を指してる
taking a night walk with you, the clock hands point to midnight.
“クロノスタシス”って知ってる？
Do you know about "chronostasis"?
知らないときみが言う
You say you don't know.
時計の針が止まって見える現象のことだよ
It's when the clock hands appear to stop.
ラララハハオ〜
Lalalahaha...
やあみんな、どうだった？楽しんでくれましたか？
Hey everyone, how was it? Did you enjoy it?
なんか後ろにいる変なのも一緒に楽しんでくれてたみたいで、めちゃめちゃ事故画激しくて、すいません
It seemed like the weird thing behind me was enjoying it too, though its face shots were super awkward, sorry about that.
ちょっとミジ、ミジと物好きのは
I mean, to be into Mizji... wait
はい、なんか変な感じするね
Yeah, feels kind of weird.
頭もぼおっとするような、あのきのこが悪かったのかな
My head feels fuzzy, was it that mushroom?
なんか変なきのこ食べちゃったんですけど、みんなも拾い食いダメだよ、ね？頭から拾って食べちゃダメだからね
I ate a weird mushroom, everyone don't eat things you find on the ground, okay? Don't pick things up from your head and eat them!
てことで、まだまだライブは続きます
With that said, the live continues!
おどりますので応援よろしくお願いします！
I'll be dancing, so I'd appreciate your support!
ねるちゃんだよー
It's Neru-chan!
ということでそれでは歌っていただけたいと思います。アイドル！
With that said, I hope you'll enjoy my song. Idol!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Blazing through the media with an invincible smile,
知りたその秘密ミステリアス
knowing all your secrets, mysterious.
抜けてる とこさえ彼女のエリア
Even your clumsy side is part of your charm.
完璧で嘘つきな君は 天才的なアイドルさま
Perfect and deceitful, you're a genius idol.
今日は何を食べた？ 好きな本は？
What did you eat today? What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
If you go out to play, where do you go?
何も食べてない？ それは内緒
You haven't eaten anything? That's a secret.
何を聞かれてものらりくらり そう淡々と
Whatever you're asked, evasive and casual,
だけどざんざんと 見えそうで見えない
yet pouring down heavily, almost visible yet hidden,
秘密の蜜 味見したい？
the nectar of secrets—want a taste?
あれもないないない これもないないない
There's none of that, none of this either.
好きなタイプは？ 相手はさあ？
What's your type? Who is the partner?
答えて
Answer me.
誰かを好きになることなんて 私わからなくてさ
I wouldn't even know what it's like to love someone,
嘘か本当か知り得ない
so I can never tell what's true or false.
そんな言葉に また一人堕ちる
Yet someone else falls for those words again,
また好きにさせる
making them fall in love once more.
誰も目を奪われていく
Everyone gets captivated by you,
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
you're the ultimate, perfect idol.
金輪際現れない 一番星の生まれ変わり
An absolute once-in-a-lifetime reincarnation of the morning star.
その笑顔で 愛してるで
With that smile, saying "I love you," —
誰も彼も虜にしていく その瞳がその言葉が
captivating everyone, those eyes and those words,
嘘でもそれは完全な愛
even if a lie, are absolute love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
"Yes, yes, that child is special."
我々は端からおまけです
"We're just extras from the start."
お星様のエクストラ 引き立て役Bです
"Extras to the star, supporting role B."
全てがあの子のお陰なわけない
"There's no way it's all thanks to her!"
妬み嫉妬なんてないわけない
"It's impossible not to feel envy and jealousy."
これはネタじゃない からこそ許せない
"This isn't a joke, which is why I can't forgive it."
完璧じゃない 君じゃ許せない 自分を許せない
"I can't forgive you if you're not perfect. I can't forgive myself."
誰よりも強い 君以外は認めない
"I won't accept anyone stronger than you."
誰もが信じあがめてる
Everyone believes and adores you,
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
truly the strongest, invincible idol.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
"You mustn't show any weakness."
知られたくないとこ見せずに
"Without showing what you don't want known,"
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
"you have to be one and only, no exceptions."
それこそ本物のアイ
That is true love.
得意の笑顔で惑らすメディア
Captivating the media with your signature smile,
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
keeping this sole secret hidden away.
愛してるってそれこそ本物
Saying "I love you" is the real deal,
意気なスリラー
a clever thriller.
流れる汗の綺麗なアクア
Aqua's sweat shines so bright,
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
hiding rubies beneath these eyelids.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing, dancing, and performing as Maria,
そう嘘はトビキリの愛
yes, lies are the finest kind of love.
誰かに愛されたこともない
Never having been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したこともない
never having loved anyone in return,
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当に なること信じてる
I believe that someday, my lies will become the truth.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる 私はそう欲張りなアイドル
Someday I'll have it all—I'm a greedy idol like that.
ちゃんと愛したいから 今日も嘘をつくの
Because I want to love sincerely, I tell lies again today,
この言葉がいつか本当に日を願って
hoping these words will truly come to pass one day.
それでもまだ君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
Even so, there are still some people I couldn't tell—just you and you.
ああやっと言えた これは絶対嘘じゃない
Ah, I finally said it. This is definitely not a lie.
愛してる
I love you.
繋いだ真っ赤な糸が 嬉しくってよしよししちゃう
The bright red thread connecting us makes me so happy, I just want to pet you.
どこにも行けないように縛って ほらあたしだけに寄り添って
I'll tie you up so you can't go anywhere; look, stay close only to me.
いい子にできてたのに
Even though you were such a good boy...
よそ見とべったり手垢 今すぐに洗わなくちゃ
Glancing away and sticky fingerprints—I have to wash them off right now!
誰に撫でられたのばっちいね 愛のメトロノーム走って
Who petted you? That's filthy. Run, metronome of love,
ふりふりして見せてよ 聞いてんの？
shake it for me and show me. Are you listening?
どうしちゃったの 絶対応いでしょう？
What's wrong? You must be in deep trouble.
どうしちゃったの いっぱい愛して
What's wrong? Love me to pieces.
あたしだけの君じゃなきゃいやだよ
If you're not exclusively mine, I won't stand for it.
ねえねえだろよねえ君はねえ誰に懐いているんだろう
Hey, hey, who on earth are you attached to?
どうしちゃったの 絶対応いでしょう？
What's wrong? You must be in deep trouble.
どうしちゃったの いっぱい愛して
What's wrong? Love me to pieces.
あたしだけの君じゃなきゃいやだよ
If you're not exclusively mine, I won't stand for it.
どうしちゃったの
What's wrong?
繋いだ真っ赤な糸が 嬉しくってよしよししちゃう
Connected by a bright red string, I'm so happy I could pet you.
どこにも行かないように縛って
Tying you up so you won't go anywhere.
ほらあたしだけに寄り添って いい子できてたのにさ
Look, you used to snuggle up only to me and be such a good boy...
よそ見とベッタリ手垢 今すぐ洗わなくちゃ
Distracted and full of fingerprints, I need to wash you right now.
誰に撫でられたの ばっちいね
Who petted you? How filthy.
ねぇあたしが君にあげた首輪したままで
Hey, with the collar I gave you still on,
おはようってキスをしたら
If we kiss and say good morning,
触り合って二人の時間
touching each other, it's our time together.
なのにあたしだけじゃ足りないの？
But is it not enough for me alone?
これが俗に言う洗脳か
Is this what they call brainwashing?
あいつがいけないのね
It's his fault, right?
誰からの通知音？
Whose notification is that?
嫉妬 moving on
Jealousy moving on.
壊しちゃってもいいかしら
Is it okay to break it?
言い訳ばっかでで見苦しいわ
Your excuses are so pathetic.
あれもこれも煩わしいわ
Everything about this is so annoying.
お仕置きしなきゃね 聞いてんの？
I have to punish you, are you listening?
どうしちゃったの ずっとずっとずっと好きだよ
What happened to you? I've loved you forever and ever.
どうしちゃったの ちゃんとちゃんとちゃんと愛して
What happened to you? Love me properly, properly, properly.
君以外なんていらない
I don't need anyone else but you.
ねえやだよ ねぇ君はねあたしのものなんだよ
Hey no way, hey, you're mine!
どうしちゃったの ずっとずっとずっと好きだよ
What happened to you? I've loved you forever and ever.
どうしちゃったの ちゃんとちゃんとちゃんと愛して
What happened to you? Love me properly, properly, properly.
君以外なんていらない
I don't need anyone else but you.
ねえやだよ ねぇ君はねあたしのものなんだよ
Hey no way, hey, you're mine!
ねぇ君が裏切るなら分かってるよね
Hey, if you betray me, you know what'll happen, right?
右左君君右下目きゅるんめちょかわ！
Right, left, right, right, right, downward glance, super cute!
タイガー！
Tiger!
ファイヤー！
Fire!
サイバー！
Cyber!
ファイバー！
Fiber!
あれやこれやいっそって結局よはごめんじゃん
This and that, in the end, it's just "sorry," right?
ずっとそばにいるなんて正直胸が切ってじゃん
Saying you'll always stay by my side honestly breaks my heart, right?
あの今宵にも上なってたいんだ背伸びのぶりんじゃ
Tonight too, I want to be above, tiptoeing like a brat,
マジな話かみだってリュックの中身パンパンでさ
Seriously, talking about gods, my backpack is stuffed full,
でも君となら目と目澄ましで息止めで心つかむ間にその中に
but if it's with you, eyes meeting, holding my breath, catching your heart inside—
見て頭の先から爪先まで君好みのカツタミスタイル
Look, from head to toe, it's your favorite custom style!
調子になって足絡ね 泣いちゃう日もあるけど
Getting ahead of myself and tangling my feet, though there are days I cry,
さらっと乱れラン君だけもさっと鳴るけど打ち込め
smoothly messing up, you're the only one... hitting it hard!
右左君君右下目きゅるんめちょかわ！
Right, left, right, right, right, downward glance, super cute!
斜め右あぞこそしてペロマジだおもめっちゃかわいい！
Diagonal right, look there, and licking... seriously, it's super cute!
深呼吸し止めて 逆に健康な
Take a deep breath and hold it, ironically healthy!
つまらない傷ついてます 炎上だけはカンベンです
Boring, getting hurt, cancellation is the only thing I want to avoid!
そう言われても約束できない 好きなことだけ罰則で痛い
Even if you tell me so, I can't promise; I want to be punished only for what I love!
こんなこころが大好きです 今日も生き抜いてえらちゃんです
I love this kind of heart; surviving today too, good job, Ela-chan!
褒められるとむしろ気が引き退いたい 下すたもぐった人間ですけど
When praised, I actually feel awkward—though I'm a person who dived underneath,
でもでも君だから 時間はすぐに息止めに 心許す君のために
but still, because it's you, time stops in an instant, for your sake, opening my heart.
ほら頭の先から爪先まで君好みのナチュラルスタイル
Look, from head to toe, your favorite natural style!
嘘じゃんパジャマのままだし 片付けする日もあるけど
No way, still in pajamas, though there are days I clean up,
でもいつでも会えるのは君だけ もさっとないけど打ち抜け
but the only one I can meet anytime is you—though unkempt, shoot through!
調子になってもいいよね？ 僕らは後で君決まり
It's okay to get carried away, right? We'll decide on you later!
右左君君右下目きゅるんめちょかわ！
Right, left, right, right, right, downward glance, super cute!
斜め右あぞこそしてペロマジだおもめっちゃかわいい！
Diagonal right, look there, and licking... seriously, it's super cute!
ああ、あ、息が詰まった...
Phew... I couldn't breathe...
ということで！
So, anyway!
アイドルペット 右左君上下目きゅるめちょかわでした！
The idol pet 'Left Right-kun, Up Down Eyes, Kyurume Chokawa'!
自分の曲なのにね、毎回言えないんですけど。
It's my own song, and yet I always stumble over it...
や、でも本当にね、あの頑張ってやりきったんじゃないかなと思って。ちょっと本当に緊張してたんですけど、ペットぐらいから、ちょっと緊張飛んできたかなって感じね。
Well, but I really feel like I pushed through and did my best. I was really nervous, but I feel like the nervousness started fading around the 'pet' part.
あとは楽しむだけだな！
Now it's just time to have fun!
最後の曲になっちゃうんですよね、もうあっという間だった！なんて、ごめん、
It's already the last song... It went by so fast! Wait, sorry—
噛み噛みでごめんって。
Sorry for stumbling over my words.
え、最後の曲はですね、なんと、すりさん作詞作曲いただいた、新曲になりまぁす！イェーイ！
Um, as for the final song... It's actually a brand-new track with lyrics and music by surii! Yay!
え、この曲はですね、世の中に対する毒がたくさん込められた、ちょっとダークな楽曲になっています。
Um, this song is a slightly dark track packed with plenty of venom toward society.
で、こちらの曲なんですけど、リリースとMVの公開はまだ少し先になるので、本日は特別に先行お披露目という形で、歌って踊らせていただきたいと思います！
And regarding this song, the release and MV premiere are still a little ways off, so today we're going to sing and dance it as a special early preview!
もう1回飲んでもいいですか？（笑）ごめんなさい、
Can I take another sip? Sorry!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
ということで、では最後も、引き続き楽しんでいってください！いきますよ、あー！
So with that, please keep enjoying the very end! Here we go, ah—!
相談ねはいはい 正論じゃ嫌な連中
Consultations, yeah right. Folks who hate righteous arguments,
同情はないない 悪いのあなた
No sympathy whatsoever. You're the bad one.
語彙が足りない 伝わらないわ
Vocabulary's lacking, it doesn't get across.
感情はないない つまらないのよ
No emotions whatsoever, how boring.
ドキドキドキ ドドキドクドキ
Thump-thump-thump, thump-thump-thump,
さよならはもう 興味がないわ
Goodbyes, I'm no longer interested in them.
ドキドキドキ ドドキドクドキ
Thump-thump-thump, thump-thump-thump,
はいそれが 私の奪っておいて無駄
Yes, that's me. Trying to snatch it away is pointless.
結論非効率ダメ
Conclusion: inefficiency is a no-go.
限界モッドク 吐かして頂戴
At my limit, modoku, let me spit it out.
面倒ねアナタの相手
You're such a pain to deal with.
嫌い嫌い嫌い 嫌い嫌い
Hate, hate, hate, hate, hate,
笑っちゃだめなの？ワレモノね
Aren't I allowed to laugh? Fragile things, aren't you.
モードクドク 至って冷静 表情も変えないで論破
Modoku, extremely calm, refuting without changing facial expression.
嫌い嫌い嫌い 嫌い嫌い 笑っちゃだめなの？綺麗なようですね
Hate, hate, hate, hate, hate, aren't I allowed to laugh? You look so pretty.
素敵なドクドクシミュミュージック
A wonderful venomous shimu-music.
会社で飲み会 嫌な話
Office drinking party, unpleasant talk.
振られて行けない あの花火
That fireworks display I was dumped and couldn't go to.
やたらと冷たい 口調だし
And a needlessly cold tone of voice.
愛されてきた これが証
Having been loved, this is the proof.
どうでもいいじゃんそんなこと 一人でみれば
Whatever, who cares about that? Watch it by yourself.
話が進まない
The conversation won't progress.
証とかかしも
Proofs and scarecrows too,
モードクドク 蓋して誘拐
Modoku, capping it and kidnapping.
表面じゃ良い子のフリして
Putting on a good kid's face on the surface,
イラッイラッイラッ イラッイラッ
Irritated, irritated, irritated, irritated, irritated,
無視っチャだめなの？バカだいいね
Aren't you allowed to ignore it? You're so foolish.
モードクドク 泣かして大変 ぎゃあぎゃあとうるさいモンスター
Modoku, making you cry is a hassle, you noisy, screaming monster.
イラッイラッイラッ イラッイラッ 黙ってお願い無駄には無駄だって
Irritated, irritated, irritated, irritated, irritated. Please just be quiet, futility is futility,
変わるわけないのにどうして
Even though there's no way it'll change, why?
結論非効率ダメ
Conclusion: inefficiency is a no-go.
限界モッドク 吐かして頂戴
At my limit, modoku, let me spit it out.
面倒ねアナタの相手
You're such a pain to deal with.
嫌い嫌い嫌い 嫌い嫌い
Hate, hate, hate, hate, hate,
ブルッちゃダメなの？ワレモノね
Aren't I allowed to tremble? Fragile things, aren't you.
モードクドク 至って冷静 表情も変えないで論破
Modoku, extremely calm, refuting without changing facial expression.
嫌い嫌い嫌い 嫌い嫌い 笑っちゃだめなの？綺麗なようですね
Hate, hate, hate, hate, hate, aren't I allowed to laugh? You look so pretty.
素敵なドクドクシミュミュージック
A wonderful venomous shimu-music.
少しは反省します バイバイ
I'll reflect just a little bit. Bye-bye.
はーい、ということで、モードク聴いてくれてありがとうございました！
Phew, so with that, thank you so much for listening to 'Modoku'!
皆さんこんにちは もう少し先になりますが
Hello everyone! It's a little further away, but
MVも楽しみに待っててください！
please look forward to the MV as well!
ではですね、ここで恒例の告知が
And now, we have our usual announcement!
あります！みんななんだろうね？わかんないよね？
Everyone, what could it be? You don't know, right?
なんだろうね？うん、わかんないよね笑
What could it be? Yeah, you don't know, right? Haha.
えー、グッズ出ます！笑
Um, merchandise is coming out! Haha.
はい！沙花叉クロヱ誕生日記念2024ということで
Yes! For Sakamata Chloe's Birthday Celebration 2024,
パパセリにまたまた押し付けしていただいたキービジュアルで
with a key visual that Papaseri forced... I mean, drew for us again,
パパセリがですね、オリジナルのアイドル衣装を
and since Papaseri drew an original idol outfit,
描いて下さったということで、グッズの紹介をさせてください！
please let me introduce the merchandise!
こちらです！えー、アクリルジオラマスタンド。
Here it is! Um, the acrylic diorama stand.
こちらはですね、キービジュアルと同じものになっているんですが、
This one is the same as the key visual,
キノコを食べていつもと様子が違う王道沙花叉になっちゃったよみたいな
with the concept that she ate a mushroom and became a royal Sakamata,
コンセプトなんですけど、ま、王道アイドルですよね、もともとね！
acting a bit different from usual—well, she's a royal idol anyway!
だから何の問題もないです！ぜひ飾ってください。
So there's no problem at all! Please display it.
そして次こちら！えー、ビッグシルエットTシャツ。
And next is this! Um, the big silhouette T-shirt.
こちらサイズはフリーサイズになっております。
This is available in free size.
沙花叉がですね、この胸ポケットの部分にいまして、
Sakamata is right here on the chest pocket,
後ろのところとかもね、キノコがどんどん食べられてる感じで、この辺に…
and on the back too, mushrooms are being eaten away more and more around here...
ちょっとコーションテープとかもあったりさりげないかなって感じでポケットの中にもね
with caution tape, making it kind of subtle. Inside the pocket,
結構凝った作りになっております。ぜひとも手に入れてください！
it's quite elaborately made. Please definitely get your hands on it!
そしてこちら、ランダムコスチュームキーホルダー！
And here, the random costume keychain!
沙花叉の今までの衣装デザインのキーホルダーということで入っております。
As keychains of Sakamata's past costume designs, this outfit is included.
衣装ごとにちゃんと言うタグとかもついてるんですよ。めちゃめちゃかわいいです！
It even has tags for each outfit. It's super cute!
よかったらぜひコンプリートしてください！そしてこちら！
If you'd like, please try to complete them! And here!
これですね、今回の一押し商品になっております。
This one is our top recommended product this time.
黒いキノコぬいぐるみバッチ！安全ピン付きでキーホルダーにもバッチにもなるよって感じで、
Black mushroom plushie badge! With a safety pin, it can be a keychain or a badge,
いろんなとこにつけてもらえたら嬉しいです！皆さんキノコ生やしてみてね！
so I'd be happy if you put it everywhere! Grow some mushrooms, everyone!
そしてこちら！今回のボイスはシチュエーションボイス「握手会」となっております。
And here! The voice pack this time is a situation voice titled "Handshake Event."
王道アイドルの沙花叉がする握手会となっておりますね。
It's a handshake event hosted by a royal idol Sakamata.
特典のボイスと比較すると面白いボイスになっているので聞いてみてください！
Comparing it with the bonus voice, it's quite interesting so please give it a listen!
そして、フルセットを買ってくださった方々にはこちらです！
And for those who purchased the full set, here it is!
フルセット購入特典は直筆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードと特典ボイス！
The full set bonus is a polaroid-style bromide card with a message and the bonus voice!
さっきのボイスとの違いを楽しんでほしいなっていうボイスと、
a voice where you can enjoy the difference from the previous voice,
いつもながら数量限定じゃない直筆メッセージ入り特典となっております！
And it's a bonus with a handwritten message, not in limited quantity as usual!
沙花叉が頑張って書かせていただきますのでよろしくお願いします！
Sakamata will do her best to write them, so thank you!
えー、改めてモードクありがとうございました！
Um, once again, thank you so much for Modoku!
沙花叉はこの曲が大好きでして、キャッチーらしさとダークさが
Sakamata really loves this song, and the catchiness and darkness
あからさまにわかりやすく出てるんですけど、それを曲中でも
are frankly and clearly shown, but concealing it
隠してっていうところがまた二面性があっていいなと思っていて、
within the song gives it a nice duality that I think is great.
ステージとかもモードクに合いそうでしょう！めちゃめちゃいい感じに
Look, even the stage looks like it fits Modoku! In a super nice way,
できたんじゃないかなと思っているんですよ。みてみて！
I think it turned out well. Take a look!
モードクもMVが出たらぜひ聞いてほしいなと思っています！
For Modoku as well, please listen to it when the MV comes out!
ということで、皆さんありがとうございました！感想たくさんつぶやいてね！
With that, thank you everyone! Please tweet lots of your impressions!
緊張したけど、みんなのコメント見てたら元気になってました！ありがとう！
I was nervous, but seeing everyone's comments cheered me up! Thank you!
では、またねー！バイバーイ！
Well then, see you again! Bye-bye!
相談ね はいはい 正論じゃ嫌な連中
Consultation? Yeah, yeah, people who hate orthodox logic
同情はないない 悪いのはアナタ
No sympathy at all, you're the one to blame
語彙が足りない 伝わらないわ
Your vocabulary is lacking, it doesn't get across
感情はないない つまらないのよ
No emotion at all, how boring
ド ドク ドク ドク ド ドク ドク ドク
Thump, thump, thump, thump, thump, thump, thump, thump
さようならはーい
Goodbye, bye-bye
もう会わない
We won't meet again
興味がないわ
I have no interest
ド ドク ドク ドク ド ドク ドク ドク
Thump, thump, thump, thump, thump, thump, thump, thump